

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Successful Commercial Ops Analytics Specialist with more than 3 years professional experience in Data Analytics and Business Intelligence. Driven selfstarter and fast learner who has managed and presented value-added insights to clients. Seeking a career change to a position involving front end web development as my long-term career

HARD SKILLS





Client • • • • • • • • Management



SOFT SKILLS

Self-taught individual

Facile learner

Time management and responsible

PASSIONATE ABOUT ...

Web Development



Data Analytics and Automation



Art and Crafts



REFERENCES

Daniel Gan (DKSH) +60126998028

Teh Li Onn (HACH)

VITIYAH MANIMARAN

Objective Front End Developer

☑ vitiyah95@gmail.com

**** 010-8837406

Petaling Jaya

WORK EXPERIENCE

OBJECTIVE FRONT END DEVELOPER

May 2022 - Current

Pursuing studies for future career goals

Pursuing my personal goals and passion that I have towards web development and would want to switch my career into professional web development job. During this period, I have utilised the time to educate myself and get certifications through online teachings. I develop my skills by working on projects and joining in coding challenges.

- · Codewars JavaScript (Rank: 5kyu)
- · LinkedIn Badge React, Front End Development, Git and GitHub, jQuery, HTML, CSS
- JavaScript Programming Advanced (StudySection) passed with global rank 296
- CSS Battle (Global Rank: 300th / 277533) https://cssbattle.dev/player/fw6JdfYvZ2UrPPctetbLkBxkq543

COMMERCIAL OPERATIONS ANALYTICS SPECIALIST HACH Malaysia Sdn. Bhd. (Danaher Co)

Nov 2021 - Apr 2022

As commercial operations analytics specialist in Hach, my major contribution was to prepare reports and lead the Contact Visibility Project for India. Below are some of the major responsibility that I carried out during my tenure as comm ops analyst.

- · Generate APAC contact visibility reports for APAC countries (India, Japan, Malaysia, Singapore, Thailand, Australia and New Zealand) on a weekly basis and drive the contact visibility efforts for all the APAC countries.
- Successfully carried out fuzzy lookup match to match the SFDC Stacking Report with Oracle ERP report to give chance for lower similarity threshold to match and automated the formula which further reduced 20% of the workload of manual checking.
- · Automated data validation Excel file to minimise wrong/error entries by the salesperson during the Contact Visibility project which reduces error key-ins by 100% and reduced back and forth confirmation by each team.
- Provide training to the sales team on how to add / update contact and their details into their SFDC account and guide on how to check the duplication for accounts.
- Drive the contact visibility by prompting sellers to update the contacts if they are dealing with a new contact.
- Help the sellers to identify unique personas and update unique personas for each KA and SOW accounts for the APAC Contact Visibility project.
- Drive the Malaysia's Contact Visibility call by updating the stats to the stakeholders.

BI LEAD FOR REGIONAL MONDELEZ PROJECT & SENIOR BI **ΔΝΔΙΥST**

Oct 2020 - Nov 2021

DKSH Smollan Field Marketing Sdn. Bhd.

As the Regional BI Lead for a high-end FMCG client (Mondelez International), I had gain a lot of experiences especially learning consumer behaviour, providing clients on the insights of out of stock issues, highly sellable SKUs, providing information on promotional execution. Mondelez International being a data driven client, it has given me chance to handle over 100+ requests on system changes and developments for both MY and SG. Some of my major contributions as Senior BI Analyst and lead for regional project.

- · Automated over 4 main reports (OOS report, OSA report, SOS report, Promo Compliance report) which was table format previously by providing scope to India's dev team within a month.
- · Introduced a new concept of documenting every system changes to keep track of what were the changes made to a particular report.
- Developed interactive dashboard using Power BI to minimise manual compilation of
- Provide User Training to SMART system users whenever a new module is introduced.
- Introduced client insights meeting to provide constant visibility to clients on weekly basis which was not a way of working previously. By introducing insights meeting, clients' expectation and trust increased which minimised complaints.

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE ANALYST

DKSH Smollan Field Marketing Sdn. Bhd.

Being in this role, my task was to ensure data integrity and provide actionable insights to the clients. During this time, I have worked across with non-essential clients such as Signify (formerly known as Philips), providing sales report and studying consumer behaviours across different regions in Malaysia. Other than that, I have handled Sime Darby and F&N as well, providing dashboards and improvising and worked way towards automation and simplify things. My extraordinary work ethics had given me chances to handle 3 different clients within a span of 1 year, was shifted on after another to automate and improvise the system. Acted as bridge between clients' expectations and development team in India, providing scope and managing costing of development

CODING SKILLS



EDUCATION

Bachelor in Biochemical and Process Engineering UNIVERSITI KEBANGSAAN MALAYSIA
GPA 2.9/4.0
Sept 2014 - Sept 2018

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1) Carried out Integrated Laboratory Project I (Microbial Population and Degradation using Rice Granules for Cooling Powder)
- 2) Carried out Integrated Laboratory Project II (Biohydrogen production from Palm Oil Mill Effluent (POME) by using algae)
- 3) Created SWOT Analysis for SME Development by Centre of Entrepreneurship and SME Development UKM

PUBLICATIONS

1) 'SMART' Manufacturing Method of Oleochemical Plants by Determining Fatty Acid Composition of C12 of Palm Kernel Stearin using Fuzzy Logic System (Artificial Intelligence using Matlab)

UKM Journal Repository - Vitiyah Manimaran, and Norliza Abd. Rahman, and Jarinah Mohd Ali, (2020) 'SMART' manufacturing method of oleochemical plants by determining fatty acid composition of C12 of palm kernel stearin using fuzzy logic system. Jurnal Kejuruteraan, 32 (2). pp. 215-220. ISSN 0128-0198

2) PVDF co PEG Glycol Membrane for Biohydrogen Purification from Palm Oil Mill Effluent Fermentation

http://www.msrjournal.com/article_43376.html https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Vitiyah-Manimaran